HeritageBox
The College of Saint Rose Archives
Heritage Box of the Sisters of St. Joseph (ACSSJ)
c. 2002
HeritageBox
The College of Saint Rose Archives
0.4 Linear feet (1 box)
This collection consists of materials created by the Association of the Colleges of Sisters of Saint Joseph (ACSSJ) to aid in educational, orientation, and enrichment activities at its member colleges.
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no access restrictions to this collection.
Biographical/Historical note
The Association of Colleges of Sisters of Saint Joseph (ACSSJ) is an association intended to link American colleges founded by the Sisters of Saint Joseph, provide resources for faculty, staff, and students at member colleges, and encourage “mission integration” on campus at each member college. The ACSSJ formed as a board of presidents from member colleges in the 1990’s. The organization appointed its first Executive Director in 2000.
Scholars from the member colleges of the ACSSJ prepared the materials in the Heritage Box and distributed them to ACSSJ’s eight member institutions in 2002. All of the member colleges were founded by some group of Sisters of Saint Joseph. The member colleges at the time the Heritage Box was distributed included Avila University in Kansas City, Missouri, Chestnut Hill College in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, Elms College in Chicopee, Massachusetts, Fontbonne University in St. Louis, Missouri, Mount St. Mary's College in Los Angeles, California, Regis College in Westin, Massachusetts, The College of St. Catherine in St. Paul, Minnesota, and The College of Saint Rose in Albany, New York. Four other American colleges founded by the Sisters of Saint Joseph were not member colleges at the time the Heritage Box was distributed.
Scope and Contents note
Series 1 includes essays, articles, prayers, promotional pamphlets and brochures, multimedia presentations and presentation guides. These materials are primarily intended to assist college administrators, faculty, and staff in creating and conducting presentations for the member college community in various areas, including orientations, prayer services, informational sessions on the ACSSJ’s Student Exchange Program, as well as to shape member colleges’ mission, policies, and practices.
Series 2 includes essays, lectures, and articles that briefly detail the history of the Sisters of Saint Joseph in France and in the United States and discuss the history and future of Catholic colleges. Bibliographies for further reading are included.
Arrangement note
The original arrangement of the Heritage Box, as it was donated to the Archives and Special Collections, has been preserved.
Folders and documents in Series 1 have been retained in their original thematic order.
Folders comprising Series 2, which were originally housed in a binder, have been retained in their original thematic and chronological order.
Association of Colleges of Sisters of Saint Joseph.; Avila University. (Kansas City, Mo.); Chestnut Hill College. (Philadelphia, Pa.); College of St. Catherine. (St. Paul, Minn.); Elms College. (Chicopee, Mass.); Fontbonne University. (St. Louis, Mo.); Medaille, Jean-Pierre, 1610-1669; Mount St. Mary's College. (Los Angeles, Calif.); Regis College. (Westin, Mass.); Sisters of Saint Joseph of Carondelet.; Catholic learning and scholarship; Catholic universities and colleges -- United States; Catholic universities and colleges -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Catholic women -- Education (Higher) -- United States -- History; College student orientation; Education, Higher -- Aims and objectives -- United States; Education, Higher -- Moral and ethical aspects; Le Puy (Haute-Loire, France); Monasticism and religious orders for women -- France -- History -- 17th century; Monasticism and religious orders for women -- France -- History -- 18th century; Monasticism and religious orders for women -- United States -- History -- 19th century; Monasticism and religious orders for women -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Saint Louis (Mo.); Women’s colleges -- United States -- History
- Heritage Box Materials
  - About the Heritage Box, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Articles and Presentations, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Association of Colleges of Sisters of Saint Joseph, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Catholic Intellectual Tradition, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mission Integration, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Orientation Guides, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Prayers and Prayer Services, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sample Mission/Heritage Items, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Student Exchange Program of ACSSJ, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Videos - History and Heritage, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Essays on the History and Heritage of the Sisters of Saint Joseph
  - Introduction, 1985-1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Early History, 10/7/1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Americanization, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Twentieth Century, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - A Future Heritage, 1985-1992 (Box 1, Folder 15)